Jesse Salazar Natividad

Software Developer

OBJECTIVE

Detail-oriented problem solver with experience developing full stack applications. Radio broadcast professional interested in transitioning into a career that will allow the opportunity to excel in software development as well as utilize previous field experience and leadership abilities.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Java Javascript
HTML CSS
Bootstrap SQL

Git and Github Technical Support
Solid OOP Principles Project Management

Spring and Spring Boot Relationship Management Leadership and Development Concept Design and Execution

PROJECTS

Team E-Commerce Website

- Collaborated with a team to design and develop a responsive e-commerce vintage game website.
- Developed the 'About Us' section, including team member cards featuring images, bios, and social links.
- Stack used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and databases.

YouTube Resource Gallery

- Developed an application to save and organize helpful resource videos from YouTube to aid in personal learning and development.
- Stack used: HTML, TailwindCSS, Javascript, iframes and local storage.

Personal Portfolio

- Created a fully responsive personal portfolio website including sections for introduction, portfolio, resume, and contact information.
- Stack used: HTML, JavaScript, and the TailwindCSS framework.

TRAINING AND EDUCATION

Generation Developer Program | July 2022 - November 2022

- Studied technologies involved in creating full stack web apps
- Implemented unit tests and deployed the apps to Netlify and others
- Developed strong interpersonal and communication skills through various team projects and presentations

WORK EXPERIENCE

New Generation Radio | June 2021 to current

Evening Broadcast Host

- Contracted with New Generation to enhance listener experience for clients strategic use of artist audio, listener discussions and newsrelated clips.
- Helped elevate station's market weight by increasing evening show rating by 15% where they consistently remain.

KBFB-FM Radio One Dallas | November 2012 – April 2021

Assistant Program Director/Music Director/Afternoon on-air host

- Managed and lead a team of 9 involved in executing various responsibilities daily.
- Continued elevating audience listening experience for audiences which resulted in 5% average ratings increase book over book.
- Cultivated and maintained strategic partnerships with label representatives to gain access to exclusive songs, artist interviews, and promotions.
- Scheduled daily music logs and coordinated weekly rotation changes by augmenting utilization of various industry software.

KKFR-FM, Riviera, Phoenix | June 2010 - May 2012 Morning Show Host

- Co-hosted daily morning show, discussed engaging topics, wrote scripts and organized fundraising and community events.
- Bolstered morning show ratings increasing the price per unit for advertising slots by 10% resulting in overall revenue growth.
- Strengthened brand awareness by arranging community gatherings, including entertainment and meet-and-greet events.
- Advocated for corporate social responsibility by coordinating charity event planning to raise funds for multiple causes.